Buster Gallon, the Betrayer
That Buffalo Crush!
He told us to leave it to him, and look what happens!
He gets sealed and that's the end of it!
Aren't you over reacting? After all, you just sat by and watched it happen.
Quiet!
I suppose... it's really sad to lose a member of our crew.
We were going to rule the world with the Metal Breath in our hands.
B-Buster... Gallon... what do you think you're doing?!
Oh, shall I explain?
This is an invention I completed today that can temporarily suspend all function of a Metal Cardbot.
With this, I can take the Metal Breath all for myself.
You son of a... You dare betray me?!
Wouldn't you say that's more like a pirate?
Farewell... Captain.
Buster Gallon!!
Could you put that down here?
What are you guys making?
A shelter!
A shelter? You mean something like a bunker?
Captain Black Hook's rule. Never lose treasure he set his eye on!
Need to build up defenses to keep planet Machina's treasure safe!
But don't you think there's been a misunderstanding?
A Metal Cardbot can't use the Metal Breath by themselves.
That's right.
If we could use the Metal Breath, I would have sealed the Cardbots myself.
So... you mean, even if Black Hook takes the Metal Breath...
...he couldn't possibly make a Metal Cardbot army?
Wouldn't explaining all of this to Black Hook make him give up?
Listen. That bad idea.
Why's that?
Us three tried really hard to steal Metal Breath.
If he learn he cannot use it, he use all his might to destroy it instead.
We can't let that happen!
Then why don't we make the first move?
Yeah, you said it! They say a good offense is the best defense!
Hey, Buffalo Crush!
Huh? What?
You know where Black Hook's hideout is.
Tell us where we can find it!
Yeah, tell us! Tell us, Buffalo Crush!
Me can't tell you!
Where are you going?!
Blue Cop, let's go follow him!
Alright.
Jun!
Mom.
Hello, everyone.
Uh... Hello.
What are you doing here?
The car that just left, wasn't that our Buffy?
Our Buffy? You mean Buffalo Crush?
Yes. I have something for him.
Can you deliver it for me?
For him? What is it?
It's just a little gift I made for him myself.
What are you doing all the way out here, Buffalo Crush?
Jun...
Here. My mom made something special for you.
It's a doll she knitted herself!
Thank you... but I can't.
What do you mean?
Black Hook is first friend I made before coming to Earth.
Me won't betray him.
We aren't asking you to do anything.
My Mom poured her heart into this doll she made for you.
So I really hope you'll accept it!
Yuri's heart?
Transform into a car! I'll put it on for you!
It look good?
Yeah! It looks great on you!
Huh? What's going on?
There's been an explosion at a warehouse in the port area.
It's on the news right now.
What?
-but the warehouse hasn't been used in a while.
-Is this it?
-and there hasn't been anyone seen in the vicinity. The police...
-That...
Our hideout!
Really? Is it close to here?
-Something bad happened to Captain!
-Hey!
Don't leave me behind again!
Blue Cop! The warehouse that blew up was Black Hook's Hideout!
What?
I'm headed there now. Meet me there!
Everyone. Let's head out!
Right!
S-s-stop!
Where are you, Captain?!
Hey, hey, look!
Could it be?...
It must be one of the robots from the rumors! Camera, now!
Already on it!
Jun. I will be arriving soon with Shadow X.
Alright. We have to chase that helicopter out of here!
Leave it to me!
Watch out!
Coming through!
Hey, watch where you're flying!
It's dangerous here. Please keep your distance.
Jun! All clear up here!
Huh?!
Aah!
Come back, both of you!
Are you okay?
My engine has been hit.
...my propeller...
To think you'd bring the Metal Breath right to me.
That makes things easier.
What happen here Buster Gallon? Where our Captain?!
It seemed to me that it would take much too long to get our hands on the Metal Breath with him in the way.
So I removed him from the equation.
What?!
And now, it's your turn!
Buffalo Crush!
Me... can't... move...
Jun! Are you alright?
Is that?...
Stay away!
Buster Gallon!
Ah. I have more customers.
What's going on here?!
Do I want to know?
Just stand back and watch!
Mega Trucker, setup!
Mega Power Shield!
Twin Vulcan!
Mega Ambler! Please find out what happened to Blue Cop!
A powerful magnetic field is blocking all movement of Metal Cardbots.
Found it! The magnetic field is coming from underground!
If you value your friends' lives, then hand over the Metal Breath!
It's a bomb!
Everyone, come back!
Huh?! Why isn't it working?
It's no use. When caught in my magnetic field, all of your functions become inactive.
This guy's good.
He really did his homework.
Of course. Black Hook knew nothing of the Metal Breath besides that it was a treasure of planet Machina.
But I'm different!
That object is nothing more than a system constructed by the mother computer, Deus Machina.
Even if it's locked to prevent Metal Cardbots from using it, there's always a way to crack the code if you put in the time.
Now. Hand over the Metal Breath!
For I, Buster Gallon, will gather the Metal Cardbots around the universe
and construct an empire across the galaxy!
Y-you're out of your mind, Buster Gallon...
I'll tell you three important things!
Are you talking to me?
What could you possibly have to say?
One!
In my experience, a talkative villain always lets down his guard and loses!
What do you mean, let down my guard?! Your fate is in my hands!
Two! I still have eight friends left in my team!
Eight? Huh. There were two taken back just now...
One is missing!
I found the magnetic field emitting device!
This can't be!
When did you?...
I'm free!
And three!
Our hearts are connected with Jun's!
Even without orders-
-We know what we need to do.
Then just try and stop me!
We won't let you win!
Phoenix Fire, setup!
Strike!
Then how about this?!
Wild Guardy, setup!
What is this?!
Jun!
Guys!
That's another invention of mine, the freeze grenade.
A genius like me always has a plan B!
Now... about that Metal Breath.
Hold... on...!
Oh, Buffalo Crush... you should really learn when to give up.
Me have... warmth of human's heart inside me.
As long as that love remain, the flames of my engine will never...
...go out!
Alright! It's our turn now!
Metal Breath, pickup!
Buffalo Crush, setup!
Buffalo Vision!
Buffalo... Vision!
Let's get him! Buffalo Moonsault!
Buffalo...
Moonsault!
Buster Blaster!
Metal Cardbot, change up!
Buster Gallon, sealed!
You're another one of our friends, now!
Finally.
I'm so sick of being unable to move!
Looks like the freeze grenade didn't last too long.
That's good!
You did it, Jun.
Not just me, it was all thanks to Buffalo Crush!
You did a great job.
You saved us all.
Thank you.
We won... but where Captain?
What's that?!
Is it an earthquake?!
B-Black Hook!
You're alive.
Buster Gallon's puny little bomb isn't enough to stop me!
Captain!
Buffalo Crush. You're still calling me Captain?!
Uh-huh!
You fool!
That's going too far.
And you, Earthling child!
I will take that Metal Breath from you one day, so you'd better be prepared!
A pirate never goes back on his word!
We'll never let you get your way! You hear that?!
The Captain hit me...